Toni Morrison Papers, 1908-2017: Finding Aid C1491
mss EADs that duplicate ones in Manuscripts
- Audiovisual Materials, 1972-2014 February 22; 19 boxes
  - Radio, 1972-2014 February 22; 7 boxes
    - With Good Reason, 2014 February 22; 1 folder 1 CD (Box 245, Folder 15)
      Sheer Good Fortune: Celebrating Toni Morrison. Featuring Nikki Giovanni, Joanne Gabin, Aniko Bodroghkozy, and Stephen Alcorn.
    - WNYC's "Sound Stages", undated; 1 box 1 audio cassette (Box 231)
      "Idea Cassette"
    - World Book Club with Mohsin Hamid, circa 2013; 1 folder 2 CD-Rs (Box 245, Folder 17)
      Note attached from BBC Producer
    - Zu Gast beim Frauenfunk, 1983 February 10; 1 box 3 audio cassettes (Box 231)
      Hessischer Rundfunk II. Toni Morrison feature.
  - Unknown, 1982 February 8-1988; 2 boxes
    - Black Women/White Women, undated; 1 box 3 audio cassettes (Box 233)
      Mary Webb/Leah Ross
    - Lay it Down: The Spector of Slave Music in Toni Morrison's Beloved, undated; 1 box 2 CD-Rs. (Box 247)
    - Questions - Berlin, undated; 1 box 3 audio cassettes (Box 233)
      May be Literarisches Colloquium, 1991?
    - Sisters: Taped Overview Intro & Outline, 1988; 1 box 1 audiocassette (Box 233)
      Theresa Willis Drew
    - Toni Morrison Unedited Master, undated; 1 box 6 audio cassettes (Box 233)
    - Toni Morrison, 1982 February 8; 1 box 3 audio cassettes (Box 233)
      Tape no. LLN31/826 B103
    - Untitled Tapes, undated; 1 box 3 audio cassettes (Box 233)
      Blank tapes?
    - Untitled Tape from Irene Jones, undated; 1 box 1 audio cassette (Box 233)
      Sent to Random House
- Floppy Disks, 1980-2000 November 9; 3 boxes
  Files from these disks are accessible on a computer in RBSC's reading room. To view the physical disks, please consult staff.
  This material is arranged alphabetically by disk titles, or groups of disks containing the same type of material, such as "Correspondence" and "Chronological Letters". The disks in groups "DataBase Files, Indexes and Programs" and "Ronnie's Disks" were maintained as per their original arrangement, in boxes with those labels.
  This series consists of files extracted from 3.5" and 5.25" floppy disks. These files include drafts from Beloved, Jazz, Paradise, Playing in the Dark, Race-ing Justice, Engendering Power, Birth of a Nation'Hood, and various academic lectures; as well as administrative databases and correspondence, likely including duplicates from letterbooks and reports found in Working Files.
  Researchers should note that partial drafts of Beloved can be found in file groups "DataBase Files, Indexes and Programs" and "Ronnie's Disks."
  Disk titles are taken from original handwritten labels, and may include dates that do not match the dates derived from the actual files. When disks were unlabeled, disk titles were occasionally supplied by the archivist, as indicated at the file-level. Description notes for individual disks contain further notations from longer labels or disk envelopes where present, or other contextual information. Disk numbers refer to the order in which disk imaging was attempted. Some disks (disk009, disk027, disk030-disk031, disk054, disk076, disk104-disk110, disk112-disk119) were unable to be successfully imaged but may be added if new machines allow them to be imaged successfully.
  - Access Test File, 2000 November 09; disk056; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    R.BOATMAN x1071 boatman@princeton.edu
  - BACKUP ARCHIVE 1990, 1991 January 23-1992 February 27; disk012; 4 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    a: / mail 90 / calls 90 12/7/90 1/23/91
  - Beloved, 1998 November 06; disk016; 3 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    for Rene's computer then load new/revised bibliography on to disk + return to E
    These files do not include drafts of Beloved. They pertain to the film adaptation of the novel and contain discussion questions.
  - Book Complete 2.1.1991, 1989 January 04-1991 March 07; disk077; 40 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    Drafts of Jazz.
  - Book Rights 1991, 1989 December 07-1994 February 28; disk006; 12 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    a: publish a: agent a: contract a: payout
  - DataBase Files, Indexes and Programs, 1980-1990 February 12; 1 box
    5.25" disks.
    Includes partial drafts of Beloved.
    - archives.dbf indexes (audio/visual) tele.dbf & indexes, 1987 December 15-1989 January 03; Disk129; 9 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Formatted audex.ndx (tlib dbf) xtlib.dbf & Index, 1988 November 10; Disk125; 3 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - biblio.dbf only, 1988 December 27; Disk123; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
    - commit.dbf & indexes, 1989 January 09-1989 January 09; Disk127; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - inltrs.dbf & indexes label1.dbf (?) lbfile.dbf & indexes, 1987 November 09-1988 December 29; Disk126; 9 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Formatted misc. indexes 1, 1980 January 01-1990 February 12; Disk128; 17 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - misc. indexes 2, 1986 July 09-1987 November 24; Disk122; 8 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Formatted TM's Personal Phone directory C: Tele, 1987 December 01-1988 December 07; Disk130; 11 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - tidex.ndx only (with tlib.db5), 1988 November 10; Disk124; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
    - tlib.dbf only, 1988 November 10; Disk121; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
    - batch files .bat copy on c:\, 1986 January 23-1988 July 28; Disk138; 8 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - biblio.dbf indexes 1 of 2, 1988 December 27; Disk137; 4 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - biblio.dbf index baudex.ndx 2 of 2, 1988 December 27; Disk136; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Contracts: DBF's NDX's PGM's, 1986 March 19-1986 July 03; Disk131; 28 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - DBASE III Files, 1980 January 01-1987 October 11; Disk134; 11 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Formatted Letter Book Index, 1980 January 01-1988 September 14; Disk142; 12 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
      LBFile.DBF LBFORM.TXT LBFORM.SCT LTNUM.NDX LTDATE.NDX LBFORM.FMT
    - C:\ Program Files, 1986 March 13-1988 July 28; Disk135; 18 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Programs A-P, 1980 January 01-1988 July 29; Disk132; 96 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Programs R-Z, 1980 January 01-1988 July 29; Disk133; 34 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Suzanne Backup 2, 1984 September 07-1986 May 15; Disk140; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Beloved, 1980 January 01-1986 May 15; Disk139; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
      Disk was originally unlabeled. Title was supplied by the archivist.
  - Drucilla's essay (Foreman.Doc), 1996 May 31; disk017; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
    Drucilla Cornell and Nikol G. Alexander's essay from Birth of a Nation'hood.
  - Chronological Letters, 1991 January 9-1997 August 18; 2 boxes
    - ARCHIVE formatted 12/7/90 a: chronlt all letters from June 1990, 1991 January 09; disk062; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - 1 a: chronlt Q+A, 1991 April 12; disk034; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
      Jan-Apr. 1991 corresp. 2.5.91 3.14.91 4.12.91 corresp. thru 4/23/91 4/30/91 new chronlt begun 4/30/91
    - 2 Q+A a: chronlt 1991, 1991 September 23; disk033; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
      formatted 7/12/91 4/26/91 Apr.-9.17.91 corresp. thru 9.17.91 new chronlt begun 9.17.91
    - 3 a: chronlt (1991), 1992 January 10; disk032; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
      From 9.17.91 to end of year updated 11/6/91 to end of 1991 1/10/92
    - A: CHRONLT (1992) 9/14/92 to 11/9/92, 1992 November 09; disk029; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - A:\CHRONLT 92-93 from 10.27.92 to 2/22/93, 1993 March 05; disk005; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - A:\ CHRONLT 92-93 2/23/93-4/13/93, 1993 January 07-1993 April 26; disk061; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: Chronlt 4/14/93-6/9/93, 1993 June 15; disk060; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 6/10/93-8/23/93, 1993 September 01-1993 September 01; disk059; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 8/19/93-10/22/93, 1993 October 25-1993 October 25; disk058; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 10/22/93-12/3/93, 1993 December 14; disk057; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 12/03/93-2/18-94, 1994 February 28; disk055; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 2/19/94-5/2/94, 1994 July 27; disk080; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 05/03/94-9/21/, 1994 July 25; disk081; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 7/26/94-9/21/94, 1994 October 04; disk082; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 9/22/94-12/01/94, 1994 December 05; disk083; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - CHRONLT A: 12/02/94-2/20/95, 1995 March 04; disk092; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
      These files are restricted until 2065 due to the presence of personally identifiable information.
    - CHRONLT A: 2/20/95-3/30/95, 1995 March 31; disk091; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 3/31/95-6/13/95, 1995 June 19; disk090; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 6/13/95-10/13/95, 1995 October 30; disk089; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 10/16/95-01/07/96, 1996 January 10; disk088; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 1/5/96-2/23/96, 1996 February 26; disk100; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 2/24/96-4/05-96, circa 1996; disk101; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 4/08/96-6/27/96, 1996 July 01; disk102; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 7/1/96-9/27/96, 1996 September 30; disk103; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 9/30/96-11/27/96, 1996 December 03; disk098; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 12/3/96-03/07/97, 1997 March 10; disk099; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: CHRONLT 3/10/97-7/11/97, 1997 July 14; disk039; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
    - A: CHRONLT 7/11/97-8/6/97, 1997 August 18; disk038; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
  - Correspondence, 1995 August-2000 January 10; 2 boxes
    - '95-'96 MSWORD Correspond a-y, 1995 August 01-1997 February 12; disk087; 112 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - 95-'96 MSWord Correspond aa-cd, 1995 September 14-1997 February 18; disk040; 55 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - 95-96 MSWord Correspond ch-kz, 1995 September 08-1996 December 09; disk041; 99 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - A-C '97, 1997 January 07-1998 March 02; disk042; 74 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - D-F '97, 1997 January 13-1997 December 17; disk043; 65 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - G-J '97, 1997 January 22-1997 December 19; disk044; 79 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
      One file is restricted until the death of the collection creator due to the presence of personally identifiable information.
    - K-MO '97, 1997 March 03-1997 December 09; disk045; 65 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - MON-P '97, 1997 January 27-1997 December 19; disk046; 55 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - R-TF '97, 1996 January 29-1997 December 16; disk047; 68 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - TG-Y '97, 1996 January 22-1997 December 19; disk048; 50 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - A-B '98, 1998 January 06-2000 January 10; disk063; 55 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - C-DA '98, 1998 January 05-1999 January 08; disk064; 56 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - DB-FRI '98, 1998 January 05-1999 January 08; disk065; 56 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - FRI-F '98, 1998 January 27-1998 December 18; disk066; 10 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - G-JK '98, 1998 January 08-1999 January 08; disk067; 57 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - JL-LN '98, 1998 January 07-1999 January 07; disk068; 58 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - LP-MO '98, 1998 January 05-1999 January 08; disk069; 48 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - MO-PB '98, 1998 January 12-1999 January 08; disk070; 53 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - PC-RV '98, 1998 January 16-1999 January 06; disk071; 55 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - RY-THUR '98, 1998 January 09-1999 January 08; disk072; 54 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - THUR-TUES '98, 1998 January 13-1999 January 07; disk073; 46 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - TUES-WED '98, 1998 January 14-1999 January 08; disk053; 48 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - WED- 2 '98, 1998 January 05-1999 January 08; disk028; 13 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
  - a: Harvd123, 1990 February 17-1991 July 11; disk023; 18 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    1 + 2 with latest corrections / 7/12/91
  - Mail and Call Reports, 1994 January 3-2000 June 20; 2 boxes
    - Calls 93, 1994 January 03-1994 February 10; disk008; 3 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
      final BU 2/28/94 Backup disk 1/4/93-12/94
    - A: Calls 95 A: Perm Backup, 1996 June 12; disk094; 4 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - Calls 98, 1998 August 28-2000 June 20; disk018; 3 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - Mail 93 Backup disk, 1994 February 25-1994 February 25; disk015; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
      1-1129 1/3/94 final BU 2/28/94 1/4/93-12/3/93
    - A: Mail 95 Backup, 1996 June 12; disk095; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - A: MAIL96.DTF Backup 1/1/96-6/12/96, 1996 June 12; disk093; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - Mail 98 Calls 98 6/18/98, 1998 June 18; disk037; 4 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
  - Meditations on Paradise speech, 1998 April 23; disk020; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
  - MICHAEL S WILK '93, 1992 March 12; disk025; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    thomas.txt / thomas.pas
    The title is crossed out on the disk.
  - MORRISONLETTERS.94, 1994 February 16-1994 July 5; disk007; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
  - OUTLTRS.DTF, 1987 March 17-1990 January 29; disk035; 12 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    A/K/A Letterbook created 3/2/89 and Important Files in C Directory, 1/29/90: COMMAND.COM AUTOEXEC.BAT MIRROR.FIL PCTRACKR.DEL AUTOEXEC.SAV CONFIG.SYS
  - Paradise, 1992 February 10-1997 July 26; 2 boxes
    - Paradise 2/9/92 / HARV Intro 2/11, 1992 February 10-1992 February 11; disk078; 6 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
      Also includes files related to the Massey Lectures/Playing in the Dark.
    - 7/26/97 Paradise Chapters Word Perfect, 1995 April 23-1997 July 26; disk001; 16 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    - 7/26/97 Paradise (copy) WP, 1995 April 23-1997 July 26; disk002; 16 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
  - Playing in the Dark, 1990 May 10-1993 June 15; 2 boxes
    Includes versions of the Massey Lectures delivered at Harvard and lectures used while teaching the class "Studies in American Africanism" at Princeton.
    - formatted 7/12/91, 1991 July 31-1991 July 31; disk079; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - formatted 7/12/91 Harvd123 as of 7/31/91, 1991 July 31; disk051; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - (Studies in Amer African, / HARVARD 1 / HARVD2 (Shadow + Flight) / HARVD 3 (Disturbing Nurses…), 1990 May 10-1991 June 27; disk074; 11 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - African1 10/17/91 / Hemingwa 10/4/91 / Poe 10/17/91 / Stowe 10/17/91, 1991 September 20-1991 October 17; disk075; 6 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    - 357 lectures, 1991 November 11-1993 June 15; disk003; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
      6/30/93 357 TWAIN 357 STEIN 357 STYRO 357 FALUK 357 BELLOW A:\*.*
    - 357 lectures, 1992 June 04-1993 June 14; disk004; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
      6/30/93 357 AFRIC 357 POE 357 HEMIN 357 OCONM 357 STOWE A:\*.*
    - Book Chapters, 1991 November 11-1993 June 15; disk085; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
      6/30/93 1 TWAIN 1 STEIN 1 STYRON 1 FAULK 1 BELLOW A:\
    - 6/30/93 1 IMAGE / 1 POE / 1 HEMING / 1 OCONNER / 1 STOWE / A:\*.*, 1992 June 04-1993 June 14; disk086; 5 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
  - Princeton Millenium Lecture Series (Slash Time Dot Space), 1998 August 28-2000 June 22; disk019; 6 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
  - PUOLB.DTF, 1989 March 30-1992 June 25; disk050; 4 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    Campus / and Community Mailing / List. / Q+A TELE.DTF / updated 6/25/92
  - Q&A Backup, 1989 March 10-1995 January 4; 1 box
    - Q&A Backup, 1990 June 19; disk036; 16 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
      Old files 1988-89 commit (88) decln88 eoy90 in2back inlt2 inltrs (88)
    - Q&A Backup, 1989 March 10-1995 January 04; disk013; 24 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
      19/vi/90 a: calls 90 cal 90 2.19.91 ltbk 90 mail 90 22.viii commit 2 2.19.91 commit callsbk9 chronll 25/vii 22/viii archiv2 2.19.91
    - Q+A Backup, 1991 August 14-1992 January 10; disk010; 7 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
      FORMATTED 2/90 Blank / calls 91 books mail 91 3.14.91 8.14.91 9.6.91 11.6.91 calls + mail 91 copied 1.10.92
  - Race-ing Justice, En-Gendering Power, 1991 December 4-1992 March 5; 2 boxes
    - Dec. 3, 1991 Swain. Wordperfect 5.1 Final Draft.Thomas, 1991 December 04; Disk120; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)
    - disk1 File name: Thomas.two, 1992 March 05; disk026; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
      formatted 3/92
    - disk 2 Thomas.two, 1992 March 05; disk014; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
  - Rene's Backup A:1, 1994 May 27; disk111; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
  - Ronnie's Disks, 1980-1989 January 12; 1 box
    - SECTION I BELOVED I BCKP, 1980-1989 January 12; Disk153; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
      BELOVED BACKUP 1 Rough Draft #1 Pages 1-180 SECTION I BELOVED1bkp To copy on Floppy c:\word\Files copy beloved.doc a: BELOVED TYPED PAGES 1-248 EDITED CORRECTED 8/29/86
    - BELOVED 2, 1986 July 03-1986 September 03; Disk147; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
      STORED AS BLV189 (starting at pg. 249) 2nd Draft typed pages 249-404 SECTION III
    - BELOVED SECTION 3, 1986 July 03; Disk146; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
      BLV302 Reformatted as 1-120 1st draft type pages 302-401
    - BELOVED3BK, 1986 September 04-1986 September 04; Disk151; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
      BELOVED3.DOC Typed pages starting at 405
    - 5 Formatted CANON FODDER Tanner Lect. Doc., 1989 January 12; Disk144; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 229)
    - MEMORANDA, 1980 January 01-1987 April 21; Disk150; 19 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - MEMORANDA AS OF 5/8/87, 1980 January 01-1987 August 13; Disk143; 19 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
    - Systems Disk Files, 1987 November 11-1988 November 14; Disk148; 34 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
      RS PERSONAL CHlabel RSlabel
    - word files, 1980 January 01-1989 January 10; Disk145; 37 digital files; 1 box (Box 229)
  - toniacv 5.18.92, 1990 April 05-1992 May 18; disk097; 2 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
  - !TMBIBLI.01B, 1996 January 22; disk096; 4 digital files; 1 box (Box 228)
    WORD 5.* for windows
  - Toni Morrison Bibliography for Syllabus, 1997 January 31; disk049; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
  - WORD PERFECT DOCS, 1989 March 2-1990 November 1; disk022; 18 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    AMAFR Stein / ARC MLKSCLC.DOC / C 357 SYLA / LECNOTES LOVELT / AMAFR2 357 Stein / ARCUL / CLS / NO / WHAT
  - WP Documents / Biblio.DBF, 1989 July 20-1989 December 13; disk011; 3 digital files; 1 box (Box 227)
    Converted to / MBIBLIO.DTF / 3/10/89
  - untitled, 1982 June 05; disk024; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 227)
  - untitled, 1996 March 14; disk084; 1 digital file; 1 box (Box 228)